#02-65, 26 Dover Crescent Singapore, 130026 (65) 83068667 vhnguyen@u.nus.edu nguyenvanhoang7398.github.io

Nguyen Van Hoang

PROFILE

I am currently a Research Scientist at PayPal and a Master student at the National University of Singapore. My research area is User-generated Content Analysis and Data Mining, where most of my publications are related to Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Information Retrieval (IR).

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore, Singapore — Master of Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence

August 2020 - June 2023 (Expected)

National University of Singapore, Singapore — Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering (honors)

August 2016 - June 2020

EXPERIENCE

PayPal Holdings, Inc. — Research Scientist

July 2020 - Present

- Noisy Text Normalization contextually standardize language syntax using state-of-the-art Sequence-to-sequence Models
- Question Answering Retrieval improve popular keyword-based retrievers with a Query
 Understanding Module and a semantic ranker built on state-of-the-art pre-trained Language Models

Undergraduate Student Researcher, NUS Web Information Retrieval / Natural Language Processing Group (WING) — Undergraduate Student Researcher

May 2017 - July 2020

• WING explores the research area of applied language processing and information retrieval to the world wide web and related technologies.

PUBLICATIONS

Nguyen, H., & Cavallari, S. (2020, July). Neural Multi-Task Text Normalization and Sanitization with Pointer-Generator. In Proceedings of the First Workshop on Natural Language Interfaces (pp. 37-47).

Nguyen, V. H., Sugiyama, K., Kan, M. Y., & Halder, K. (2020). Neural side effect discovery from user credibility and experience-assessed online health discussions. Journal of Biomedical Semantics, 11(1), 1-16.

Nguyen, V. H., Sugiyama, K., Kan, M. Y., & Halder, K. (2018, October). Treatment Side Effect Prediction from Online User-generated Content. In Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Health Text Mining and Information Analysis (pp. 12-21)

AWARDS

ASEAN scholarship

August 2016 - June 2020 (Expected)

 Covering full tuition fees and yearly allowance during undergraduate study at National University of Singapore

Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Prize (Individual) — Leveraging Social Context in Fake News Detection with Graph Representation

Academic Year 2019/2020

• Awarded to top undergraduate students for their outstanding research

Deans' List

Semester 2. Academic Year 2019/2020

Student Honours Roll

Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Prize (Group) — Development of a novel artificial neural network for accurate diagnosis of acute medical conditions, rapid triaging, and right-siting based on patient-reported symptoms

Academic Year 2016/2017

Awarded to top student groups for their outstanding research